# SAMUEL REID

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

☑ exgin3538@gmail.com https://samuelreid.netlify.app/ (770) 899 - 5056 Atlanta, Georgia in sreid20 exgin

# **ABOUT ME**

The challenge of developing a program from the ground up sparked my interest in being a Software Engineer. The feeling of finally being able to solve a bug or learn a new way to implement code is extremely rewarding for me. This lead me to gain experience developing full stack web applications with modern frameworks and technologies.

## **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, PHP

FRONT END: Bootstrap 4, React, Redux, Bulma BACK END: Flask, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Django DATABASES: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite

VERSION CONTROL & DEPLOYMENT: Git, Github, Heroku, Netlify TESTING LIBRARIES: Jest, Jasmine, Supertest, React Testing Library

ADDITIONAL TECHNIQUES: Creating RESTful APIs, Writing unit & integration tests, Makingauthentication and authorization, Applying OOP,

Following TDD

## **PROJECTS**

Black Lives Matter Aug. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Created a Full Stack website to inform users on the current civil crisis happening
- Developed a backend API to handle secret API keys & routes needed
- Inform user's on how they can help & support the cause
- Stack Used: ReactJS /w Material UI & Bootstrap, Redux, NodeJS /w ExpressJS, PostgreSQL

## One Stop Skate Spot - Skate Park Locator

May 2020 - May 2020

- Created a Full Stack website application using various API's to create a skateboarding website for all skill levels
- Developed a small backend API utilized for querying needed data for the map
- Collected data from Yelp's API to view the closest location needed for the user
- $\bullet \ Stack \ Used: Java Script \ w/j Query \ \& \ Bootstrap, Python \ w/ \ Flask, SQLAlchemy, Postgre SQL \\$

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Springboard, Software Engineering Career Track Fellow

Feb. 2020 - Present

- Developed 2 personal capstone projects to refine and enhance my technical skills
- $\bullet \ Completing \ 800 + hours \ of software \ engineering \ curriculum \ and \ training \ while \ working \ with \ established \ industry \ experts$
- Mastering skills within front-end web development, back-end web development, and full stack development

#### Recreational Center: Jim Huie, Rec. Lifeguard, Jonesboro, GA

Sep. 2019 - Present

- Responsible for the supervising & monitoring the safety of the 50+ of patrons daily
- $\bullet \ \text{Administering emergency oxygen, first aid, CPR, AED if required for any life threatening situations}\\$

#### UPS, Package Handler & Sorter, Forest Park, GA

Nov. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- Managed the loading and sorting for over 2500+ packages to ensure that customers receive the correct packages, intact, and on time
- Trained 10+ new hires as package handlers and sorters to help them acclimate to the environment and ramp up quickly on the job to assist the team

### DUA Fayetteville, Server, Fayetteville, GA

Oct. 2017 - May 2018

- Ensured excellent interpersonal skills.
- Maintained professional working relationships with colleagues, customers, and vendors

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Clayton State University**

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2019

Associates Information Technology

Relative Coursework: Computer Science I & II, Intermediate Networking & Security, Intermediate Web Development, Foundations of Database-Systems Design